在上一集中
Previously on "Transformers Prime..."
隔板 救护车人呢？
Bulkhead, where is Ratchet?
他被掳走了
He's gone.
如果威震天真的想要重铸终极之锁
If Megatron is truly rebuilding the Omega lock
那么合成能量可能是一种不可或缺的原料
synthetic Energon might be a necessary component.
大脑神经接入器获取了什么信息？
What did the cortical psychic patch yield?
只确认了合成能量的配方确实不稳定
Only that the synthetic Energon formula is unstable.
如果应答器还在激光鸟身上
If the transponder were still attached to Laserbeak
我们就可以跟踪它
we could follow it.
也就是说 我们要让这个小玩意飞回虎子的指挥中心
So, we're gonna let this doohickey fly back to 'Con central...
并给我们指明救护车的位置
And lead us right to Ratchet.
你们应该期盼我们被毁灭的家园恢复昔日的辉煌吧？
You would like to see the ruins of our devastated home world restored to their former brilliance.
你不过是想再次征服塞博特恩
You would just try to conquer Cybertron all over again.
这个事实不会改变
But that does not change the fact
你或许是让塞博特恩重见天日的唯一希望
that you may be Cybertron's only hope of ever seeing life again.
我答应你
I'll do it.
真的不用给侦察器装个GPS吗？
You sure we don't need to install a GPS on our scout here?
太冒险了
Too risky...
这种小伎俩对双方来说 太容易识破了
both sides are getting real good at rooting out that kind of trick.
况且 我们用不着追踪装置
Besides, we don't need a tracker.
我们有擎天柱
We have Optimus.
但虎子不会发现你吗 大块头？
But won't the 'Cons see you coming, big guy?
等他们发现时已经晚了
Not until it's too late.
我们会做好准备 接到命令立即行动 长官
We'll be prepared for immediate mobilization upon your command, sir.
祝你好运 擎天柱
Good luck, Optimus.
注意安全
Be safe.
无论结局如何
Whatever the outcome
相信救护车一定会为你们的努力而骄傲
know that Ratchet would be most proud of your contribution.
来吧 孩子 把这玩意儿送上天
Come on, kid. Let's light this thing.
把量子-数字测量仪给我拿来
Fetch me the quantum-cyber measure.
哼
Hmm.
我像是给你打下手的吗 汽车人？
Do I look like hired help to you, Autobot?
击倒 必须满足贵客的要求
Knockout, attend to the needs of our esteemed guest.
遵命…
As you command.
已经得知 这种塞博特恩网状物
So, we know this cyber matter to be produced
是非典型分子置换反应的产物
by an atypical molecular-displacement reaction.
大量实验证据表明
Extensive empirical evidence indicates
合成能量配方的不稳定性是问题的根源
the fundamental instability within the Synth-En formulation to be the cause.
双盲分析做了吗？
Double-blind analysis?
当然 实验结果只是证实了我最初的假设
Naturally. The results only confirmed my original hypothesis.
一旦修正了错误变量
Once the erroneous variable has been corrected for
稳定的合成物将会与C.N.A.完美结合
the stabilized synthetic material will bind properly with cybernucleic acid.
从而产生稳定的塞博特恩网状物
And produce a stable form of cyber matter.
不可思议
Remarkable.
没错 似乎是天意
Yes. Quite an act of providence.
知道吗 要不是让你们干掉了那些野兽
And to think that, had we not let you destroy the beasts
也不会取得今天的成果
none of this would be possible.
“让”我们？
Let?
我是说…
Uh, what I meant to say was...
你之前索要的样本可不会凭空蹦出来 是吧？
those specimens you requested earlier aren't going to prepare themselves, are they?
任务艰巨 时间紧迫 医生
There is much to do and little time, Doctor.
该继续工作了吧？
Shall we get back to work?
当然
Certainly.
擎天柱 你消失有一阵子了
Prime. Haven't heard from you in a while.
一切还顺利吗？
Everything all right up there?
目前还好 福勒探员
So far, Agent Fowler.
虎子识别了激光鸟的信号后会怎样？
What happens when the 'Cons I.D. Laserbeak's signal?
只希望擎天柱能尽快看到战舰
We're counting on Optimus making visual contact with the warship
赶在被雷达发现之前
before its radar can detect the ship.
老大不会有事的
The boss will be fine.
我担心的并不是擎天柱
It's not Optimus I'm worried about.
击倒 我需要一个新鲜的C.N.A.样本
Knockout. I require a fresh CNA sample.
噢…我…
Ohh, I...
击倒 把这个拿来 击倒 把那个给我
"Knockout, bring this. Knockout, get that."
很显然 取货成了我的新特长
Apparently, fetching is all I'm good for lately.
不久前 我还是这个实验室的老大
It wasn't all that long ago I used to run this lab.
现在人人都拿我当跑腿儿的使唤
Now I am everyone's gofer.
有事么？
Yes?
绝缘探针！
The... the isoprobe!
我…没找到
I-I... don't see one.
我就知道…
What a surprise.
哦
Ohh.
您还要点什么？
Anything else?
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
我们即将进入一个新纪元！
We stand at the very precipice of a new age!
你是说扫描器探测到了激光鸟的信号？
What do you mean, our scanners have detected Laserbeak's Signal?
红蜘蛛
Starscream.
你不是摧毁汽车人基地了吗？
You did destroy the Autobot base
有漏网之鱼吗？
did you not?
已经夷为平地了 陛下
With great fervor, my lord.
您何出此言？
Why do you ask?
激光鸟的通讯频率出现在了雷达上
Because Laserbeak's frequency has been detected on radar.
这不可能！
But that's not possible.
他不就在声波的胸前吗
He's right here in Soundwave's torso.
也就是说 这应该是汽车人耍的诡计
Which is why this would appear to be an Autobot trick
目的是查探我们的位置 营救那个俘虏
designed to uncover our position and rescue a certain prisoner.
不过 我倒想问问
But then one has to wonder
他们怎么可能实施如此复杂的行动？
how would they possibly manage to execute such a complex task
现在他们连基本设施都没有！
without the proper facilities!
我…呃…
I, uh...
请允许我去查明原委
Allow me to troubleshoot.
哦…谜题的最后一环
Oh... The final piece of the puzzle.
多谢了 霸天虎工程技术
Thank you, Decepticon engineering.
震荡波
Shockwave!
终极之锁的组装已进入最终阶段
Assembly of the Omega lock is  entering the final stage.
我需要你前去指导
Your guidance is required.
遵命 我的君王
Understood, my liege.
击倒 我不在时你来监督客人
Knockout, supervise our guest in my absence.
哇 我真是受宠若惊
Wow. Thanks for the big vote of confidence.
我决不能让稳定的配方落到威震天手中
I can't allow Megatron to possess the stabilized formula.
现在不行
Not now...
以后也不行
or ever.
我的天啊 出什么事了？
For the love of... what is happening?!
配方不稳定…
The formula's instability...
一定是引起了连锁反应！
it must have triggered a chain reaction!
卫兵 快来帮我灭火
Guards, help me extinguish this inferno
不然它会烧毁我们的项目…
before it scorches the project...
还有我的涂装！
And my finish!
擎天柱！
Optimus Prime!
你竟敢苟活于世！
How dare you continue to live?
给我把那个汽车人轰成碎片！
Blast that Autobot into oblivion!
那个频率并非来自擎天柱
The frequency isn't emanating from Prime
而且还在移动
and it's still on the move.
干掉他！
Finish him!
如果不能在信号源发现战舰之前找到它
If I cannot find the source of the signal before it finds the warship
威震天会要了我们脑袋的！
Megatron will have our heads!
威震天陛下
Lord Megatron
呃 出了点小麻烦
Uh, there has been a situation...
呃 其实是个小事故 我真的…
Uh, more like an accident, really. I...
别绕弯子！
Spit... it... out!
俘虏逃跑了！
The prisoner has escaped!
现身吧 现身吧 别藏了
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
这把老骨头还挺灵活
Not bad for an old bot.
如果你杀了我
If you terminate me
你就永远也得不到配方！
you'll never get your hands on the formula!
哦 别把话说那么绝 医生
Oh, I wouldn't be so certain, Doctor.
我们的专家正在努力揭开你的…
My experts are working diligently to disentangle your...
装模作样的面具
false trail as we speak.
找到了
There you are.
给我下去吧
And down you go.
不！
No!
啊！我需要环陆桥 快！
Aah! I need a ground bridge... now!
啧 啧 啧…想得美
Tsk, tsk, tsk. Nice try.
我还是把它放回原处吧
I'll just put this back where it belongs.
频谱分析确认
Spectrum analysis confirms
合成能量已经稳定
that the synthetic Energon is stable.
配方制作完毕
The formula is now complete.
什么时候能开始生产？
And your timetable for production?
有了超级加速科技的协助
With the aid of hyper-acceleration technology
不会太久
not long.
哦 可惜你无法眼看着自己的研究成果开枝散叶
Ohh, a pity you won't live long enough to witness the fruits of your labor.
尽管我很感激你做出的贡献 医生
But as much as we appreciate your contributions, Doctor
但我有个诺言必须要兑现
I've made a promise to someone that I intend to keep.
你是不是感到回天无力 汽车人？
Do you feel defenseless, Autobot?
很好 现在你知道 我的巨狰狞弟兄们
Good. Now you know what my fellow Predacons endured...
被你们屠杀前作何感受了！
right before you massacred them!
擎天柱呼叫基地 请回答
Optimus to base... come in.
指挥官 你已经确认了战舰位置吗？
Commander, have you determined the warship's location?
没有 通天晓
No, Ultra Magnus.
应答器被毁掉了
The transponder has been destroyed.
寻找救护车的任务几乎退回了原点
We are no closer to finding Ratchet than when we began.
威震天陛下
Lord Megatron
数字化地球所需的塞博特恩网状物已开始合成
synthesis of the cyber matter required to cyberform Earth has commenced.
干得漂亮 震荡波！
Splendid, Shockwave!
把终极之锁移动到指定位置
Move the Omega lock into position.
我要做好一切准备
I want to be ready.
终于 可以摆脱这个悲惨的种族了…
At last, good riddance to a wretched species.
值得一提的是他们倒很擅长制造帅气的车辆
Although I will say they manufacture some fine-looking automobiles.
给我个痛快吧
Just get it over with.
我也没脸活下去了
It's not like I could ever live with myself
现在我成了人类灭绝的帮凶
knowing the role I played in humankind's extinction.
但如果你想为同伴报仇
But if you want to avenge your cohorts
杀掉我并不是终点！
don't stop with me!
威震天才是你的最终目标！
Keep avenging all the way to Megatron!
什么？！你什么意思？！
What?! What do you mean?!
是你那高高在上的首领 想要除掉你们巨狰狞
Your high and mighty leader wanted your Predacons exterminated...
我们仅仅是他的棋子而已！
and simply allowed us to do his dirty work for him!
你是为了保命才信口开河！
Nothing but a false claim to save your own spark!
咳
Hea...
你自认为是智慧生物 不是吗？！
You consider yourself an intelligent being, don't you?!
那就放下你的野兽本能
Then rise above your base instincts...
分析当时的情况
and analyze the situation.
那天我们拼命地追查
We followed the trail that day with the desperate hope
只希望能找到一座能量矿
that it would lead to an Energon mine.
从没想过会发现震荡波的实验室
We had no idea we would find Shockwave's laboratory.
这个巧合太离谱了！
The coincidence barely seems plausible!
因为那根本不是巧合！
Because it wasn't a coincidence.
故意用能量引诱我们过去的…
The Energon was clearly planted to lure us there...
就是威震天！
by Megatron!
我的君王为何要毁灭我们？
Why would my liege wish to destroy us?
在见识过你的强大本领之后
Having just been on the receiving end of your might
我忽然有了个想法…
one theory springs to mind...
威震天惧怕你
Megatron fears you
还有你的同类
and any like you.
威震天陛下 冲云霄在大开杀戒
Lord Megatron, Predaking is on a rampage and moving rapidly... toward the...
他正快速冲向…噢…啊！
ohh! Aah!
汽车人基地 能收到吗？
Autobot base, do you read?
我是救护车 有人能听到吗？
This is Ratchet. Can anyone hear me?
清晰无比 老朋友
Loud and clear, old friend.
- 太好了！\N- 是救护车！
- Whoo\N - hoo!\N - Yes! Ratchet!
我就知道他没事！
I knew he was all right!
听我说
Listen to me...
威震天设法在他的战舰上重建了终极之锁
Megatron has managed to rebuild the Omega lock on board his warship.
我已经关闭了霸天虎的护盾
I've deactivated the Decepticon shielding system.
你们应该可以定位我的坐标
You should be able to get a fix on my coordinates.
擎天柱 必须尽快行动！
Optimus, you must hurry!
威震天正准备把地球数字化 十万火急！
Megatron is preparing to cyberform Earth as we speak!
救护车…
Ratchet...
汽车人 锁定坐标
Autobots, lock on to those coordinates
准备突袭战舰
and prepare to storm the warship.
领袖下令了
You heard our leader.
既然要打 就战个痛快！
We're going in, and we're going in heavy.
武装起来！
Gear up.
他们也不知道告个别
They can't leave without saying goodbye.
没时间了 也没有必要
No time for that, and no need.
他们会回来的
They'll be back.
开启环陆桥
Initiating groundbridge.
领袖卫队的成员们
Members of team Prime
汽车人和人类朋友
Autobot and human
能领导你们我深感荣幸
it has been my honor to lead you.
今时今日 两个世界的命运岌岌可危
On this day, the fates of two worlds hang in the balance
而这场战役很可能是我们的最后一战
and the battle to come may very well be our last.
为了地球 为了塞博特恩
But for Earth, for Cybertron
为了我们的战友救护车
for our comrade, Ratchet
我们必须攻下霸天虎的战舰
we must take the Decepticon warship.
您确定和那个半兽人正面对决
Are you sure confronting the beast-bot directly
是明智之举吗 威震天陛下？
is the best option, lord Megatron?
让我们看看 这位自封的王者
We shall see how his majesty
如何应付我们手中最强大的武器…
fares against the most powerful weapon in our vault...
黑暗星辰剑！
the Dark Star Saber!
威震天！
Megatron!
我这就去取刚才提到的那个小玩意儿
I'll just go fetch that little something we talked about.
真的是你下令毁灭我的野兽大军吗？！
Is it true that you ordered the annihilation of my army?!
确实如此 而我唯一的错误就是没有斩草除根
Indeed, and my only mistake was not seeing the extermination through.
我要把你大卸八块！
I will tear you apart!
我…啊！
I... aah!
表现不错
That's the spirit.
但作为卡隆角斗场的冠军
But I was a champion of the pits of Chaon
我拥有的不仅是蛮力…
not only due to my savage might...
还有脑子！
but also my cunning!
你该听从我的忠告 在我面前保持野兽形态
You should have heeded my advice and faced me as a beast.
太精彩了 我的君王！
Bravo, my liege.
这可不是常有的事 见证已经绝迹的种族再遭灭顶！
It isn't every day one witnesses the extinction of a species all over again.
终极武器登场喽！
One ultimate weapon coming right up.
呃 满身鳞片的黑大个哪儿去了？
Uh, where's tall, dark, and scaly?
汇报情况！
Report.
威震天陛下 战舰正遭受攻击
Lord Megatron, the ship is under attack...
是汽车人
by the Autobots.
战舰不是处于隐形状态吗
But the warship is cloaked.
这怎么可能？
How is that possible?
那个军医还活着！
The medic lives!
动用所有剩余力量！
Mobilize what remains of our forces!
全力保护终极之锁 不惜一切代价！
The Omega lock must be defended at all costs!
如果擎天柱想主动开战
If Optimus Prime wishes to wage a battle
赌上地球和塞博特恩的命运
for the fate of both Earth and Cybertron...
那么我就如他所愿
then I shall oblige him.
在此与他决一死战！
This will be our last stand!